LanSchool Air Data Processor Agreement FAQ V002 March 2024 1

FREQUENTLY ASKED QUESTIONS \& ANSWERS ON

THE LANSCHOOL AIR DATA PROCESSING AGREEMENT (DPA)

What is the LanSchool DPA?

This LanSchool Air Data Processing Agreement and its annexes (“DPA”) forms part of the Stoneware

Sales Agreement or other written or electronic agreement between Stoneware, Inc. and Customer for

the purchase of LanSchool Air services from Stoneware, Inc., a Lenovo company. The DPA is designed

to reflect the parties’ agreement in relation to the privacy and security standards that will apply to the

responsible use and protection of Customer personal data and related confidential information to be

processed by Stoneware under the agreement. The DPA supplements any agreement between the

parties with respect to the processing of Customer data and will be effective from the moment that

Customer accepts LanSchool Air Terms of Service. To facilitate new customer relationships and the

contracting process, the DPA has been pre-signed on behalf of Stoneware. The DPA may be read in

conjunction with the LanSchool Air \& Lenovo NetFilter Privacy Statement (“Privacy Statement”).

Is the LanSchool Air DPA global in scope or specific to particular regions?

The DPA is intended to apply globally since Stoneware and Lenovo are global companies. Therefore, the

DPA reflects applicable global standards for privacy and security. However, we have also developed our

privacy and security programs and this DPA with particular privacy laws (e.g., EU’s GDPR, Brazil’s LGPD,

California’s CCPA/CPRA, other national and local education privacy laws) and security standards (e.g.,

ISO, NIST) in mind. If a customer has additional or equivalent requirements or standards it believes will

need to be met by Stoneware and Lenovo , we will review and respond to those requests as appropriate.

What Customer Data does LanSchool Air collect and store?

Please see the Privacy Statement and Annex A (Processing Details) of the DPA. Stoneware and Lenovo

process only necessary information to keep the LanSchool Product(s) working their best and to help

customers make the most of them.

Do Stoneware and Lenovo share Customer Data with any third parties?

For more information about how we share Customer Data in the context of LanSchool Air, please see

Annex B of the DPA and the Privacy Statement.

Stoneware and Lenovo contract with other companies, who act as our suppliers to perform services for

Stoneware and Lenovo, such as data hosting, processing, marketing, promotions, event sponsorship,

product development, and analytics.

LanSchool Air Data Processor Agreement FAQ V002 March 2024 2

Such services may require Stoneware to share customer information with its service providers. In such

cases, we take steps to ensure that these suppliers to Stoneware are adhering to Stoneware’s standards

for robust privacy and strong security. Appropriate privacy, security and/or data processing agreements

are signed to address responsibilities of the supplier to protect and responsibly process data of the

Customer.

Stoneware also relies on other Lenovo businesses and operations globally to provide services to support

LanSchool products and services. LanSchool may also contain various links to third-party websites or

services that may provide additional information, services, or promotions. These sites and services may

be operated independently of Stoneware and Lenovo and have their own separate privacy and data

collection practices. Any information customers provide to these websites and services will be governed

under the terms of their privacy policy, if any. Stoneware and Lenovo have no responsibility or liability

for the actions or policies of these independent sites and services and are not responsible for the

content or privacy practices of such sites.

Do Stoneware and Lenovo transfer Customer Data internationally?

As a global enterprise, Lenovo and Stoneware necessarily process Customer Data in and/or transfer such

data to the locations where it does business. These may include data centers and/or functions located in

the EU/EEA/UK, United States, Asia-Pacific (Australia), and elsewhere as applicable. The specific storage

location is based on the customer ́s country location (e.g., European-sourced data to be standardly

stored in the United Kingdom); or the customer may request the data to be stored in another location.

Lenovo manages these transfers within the framework of the law and uses appropriate compliance

mechanisms (including but not limited to Standard Contractual Clauses in our intra-group agreements

and in our supplier agreements) to effectuate transfers of personal data across borders. If a particular

country or customer has a data localization requirement that may restrict the transfer of Customer Data

across borders, Lenovo will meet that requirement to the extent applicable or practicable. Otherwise,

Lenovo will meet the requirements for Customer Data processing, privacy and security as set forth in the

customer’s contract and data transfer agreement with Lenovo, and Lenovo will limit its processing to

only established legitimate interests.

What is the purpose of Annex D of the DPA and is Annex D necessary in all cases?

Annex D represents contractual provisions serving as safeguards for safe personal data transfers to third

countries, which are required by applicable data protection laws.

It has been developed with Europe’s General Data Protection Regulation (GDPR) in mind and is

generally applicable to only processing activities that may involve the transfer of Personal Data from the

European Union and European Economic Area and/or other countries with similar adequacy or

equivalency standards pertaining to cross-border data transfers. Specifically, Annex D incorporates EU

Standard Contractual Clauses ("SCCs") as set out in the Commission Implementing Decision (EU)

2021/914 of 4 June 2021 on standard contractual clauses for the transfer of personal data to third

countries pursuant to Regulation (EU) 2016/679 of the European Parliament and of the Council, the UK

LanSchool Air Data Processor Agreement FAQ V002 March 2024 3

International Data Transfer Addendum to the European Commission’s Standard Contractual Clauses for

International Data Transfers and other similar equivalency standards under applicable data protection

laws.

Will Stoneware sign the Customer’s data processing agreement instead of the LanSchool Air

DPA?

Stoneware believes that it is necessary to establish consistent standards of responsible use and

protection of all our Customers’ data globally and to avoid the need to enter potentially conflicting

standards of privacy and security compliance with our customers. Therefore, while we will certainly

take into consideration Customer requests to enter into their own data processing agreement

templates, Stoneware starts from the premise that the LanSchool Air DPA should apply.

Does Stoneware allow the Customer to propose edits to the LanSchool Air DPA?

Yes. Stoneware welcomes reasonable proposals by the Customer to edit the DPA if necessary.

Does the LanSchool Air DPA reflect strong privacy and security standards?

Please see Annex A (Technical and Organizational Measures) of the DPA. Stoneware and Lenovo have

placed customer privacy and security at the forefront. Therefore, we have developed robust privacy and

security programs that incorporate industry-class policies, procedures, processes, technologies, training,

and other controls. We have developed the DPA with these controls in mind.

Is LanSchool Air compliant with the EU GDPR and/or other data protection laws?

Lenovo and Stoneware are committed to being trusted partners, innovators, and suppliers of secure,

high-quality products and services globally. Security and privacy are at the center of our philosophy,

reflecting the commitment to providing products and services that meet or exceed industry standards

for customer security, privacy, and data protection. As such, our privacy and security programs aim to

meet the highest standards. While no universal certification exists that would demonstrate Stoneware ́s

and/or Lenovo ́s compliance with applicable data protection laws and other related

standards,Stoneware and Lenovo have implemented robust controls and safeguards that align with

ISO27001 and/or other internationally recognized standards.

LanSchool Air Data Processor Agreement FAQ V002 March 2024 4

Where can I learn more about privacy and security at Stoneware and Lenovo and how Lenovo

will process Customer data?

If you require further information regarding our privacy and security standards, please contact your

Stoneware account representative who will be able to address your questions and provide you with a

more details about privacy and security at Lenovo. Please note that you can also find more information

about LanSchool Air’s privacy and security practices by reviewing the Privacy Statement.

Will Stoneware update the LanSchool Air DPA on a regular basis?

We may update the DPA to accommodate new legal requirements or as necessary to reflect operational

updates. If you have an active LanSchool Air subscription, we will let you know via email or via in-

product notification. You can find archived versions of the DPA here.
